[Music]
welcome to the special video series
future focus brought to you by ICICI
Lombard in this very first episode we
have with us Greece night chief of
service technology and operations at
ICICI Lombard he's going to share with
us his expert views on how to run a
smooth ship during the pandemic and also
why digital services are important
during these trying times welcome to the
show
Harish and tuition any please tell us
how I say I say Lombard is using
technology to serve customers this whole
scenario due to the pandemic lockdown is
quite unique I don't think any
organisation in spite of very
well-written BCP policies and what have
you ever wrote a scenario where all the
promises would be available but human
agents would not be able to access any
promise so typically BCP scenarios look
at situation where one premises is out
of reach or destroyed or
a datacenter is out of commission or
whole lot of situations where one
doesn't to kind of expect that
everything is remote but what also I
mean what has helped is in having the
PCPs though it did not admit is the
scenario it did in research a set of
protocols to be followed by the crisis
is noticed and that is what helped us
through in very swiftly responding to
the whole scenario as it panned out
we immediately I mean when we had the
first sense of something like this
coming me immediately
sent almost 50 percent of our staff to
work from home across the country we
also fortunately were able to order some
additional laptops and got them
delivered just before and as the
countrywide logged on it so
a few more of the staff who needed to be
enabled to work from home could be given
these laptops so in a sense we could
have a good proportion of our stuff to
be enabled to directly work from home
with laptops and using either VPN or
Internet facing applications as the case
may be with the appropriate security
functionality in want to work from home
regarding our partners and we have a
huge agent Network and channel so there
we have been over a period of time
digitizing a whole lot of functionality
out there that stood us in good stead at
this point in time where most of our
operations with our agents though we are
not able to physically mo any paper or
we are able to do that digitally so
whether it is through the agent portal
that we have given them or through a
mobile app or through email bot that is
used especially in our SME business so
there are various tools that agents have
at their fingertips to kind of
communicate with us digitally to process
information digitally to issue policies
districts that has helped us in good
stead to manage this whole scenario in
the pandemic without having to actually
access our offices and finally the
customers always have our website if
they want to directly access and
purchase policies on the website or
through the mobile app and that has been
working constantly through this period
and finally the call center we have an
in-house call center and again we were
able to get a significant amount of call
center capacity also working from home
right from day one so that has helped
service the because one important part
of the entire operation is the claim
service and especially our time like
when people require access for health
claims that we had to keep that up and
running conscious so our health claim
processing witches are because we have
annouced EPA as well which process the
health claims as well as the call center
we were able to get functioning on day
one of the lockdown from home so that
that process also can turn uninterrupted
so we've been kind of because of our
huge investment in digitization
automation we have been able to get all
the constants of it whether it is the
employees the partner network or the
customers kind of move seamlessly to
this lockdown scenario that we have okay
and talk to us about some of your CRM
initiatives what measures have you taken
to prove the experience you spoke about
digital you know where apps people use
apps there must be a certain spike at
this point of time talk about your
experience in terms of you know how much
how much of these customers are coming
online today and why yeah like I said
see there are there's certain section of
the customers who comes online they have
been coming online that is increased but
really where greater this has been is
trying to get our agency network
completely says so and we have different
solutions for different kinds of agents
who primarily do the motor business
there it's largely through a portal
which we call I partner where they have
all the functionality that they require
including if they need to have some
special approvals everything is kind of
put in that one portal that's one place
where they go and they can issue
policies immediately to the customer
they can and in this situation where
they're not able to interact with the
customer directly they also have to work
from their home they are able to talk to
the customer on phones and within the
policy to send a payment link to the
customers or customer can make the
payment on his or her device
and the policy gets issued and sent to
the customer same is the case in for
help the business they're the agents
more comfortable because of the
different nature of that they are more
comfortable doing the business from
mobile so we have a complete mobile app
which they have and everything can be
done you know onboarding of customers
can be done completely from the mobile
app I did mention that we have an email
bought for our semi customers STS any
agents and that again is a different
solution because there it's not a it's
not an individual saying it's selling to
small and medium enterprise and
typically the sale is a bit more complex
because the product is not a simple
motor product to help rocket fire and
burglary or sometimes even more complex
so there they need to be sitting across
the customer at most of times you're in
this situation they'll be calling the
customer and it's a bit of a complex
form to fill so instead of having a web
app or a web web screen or app to fill
the easiest thing for the person to do
is fill in the email so what we have
done is just he fills the details
required for the code and the email and
sends it to a particular email id
there's a bot which picks up the mail
understands what policies required goes
to the relevant system picks up the code
and sends it across on the mail this all
happens in five minutes so the agent is
again as he said across he gets the mail
saying that okay this is the code he can
then discuss it with the customer and if
the customer is okay then all he needs
to do is put the check number and just
send the email back a policies issued
within minutes and sent back so all
these happens completely on email its
most simple interface as you might say
for doing a complex piece of this like a
SNe policy so there multiple ways of
addressing the same need and that is
basically the customers need to get a
policy issue that we have been
able to fulfill through our various
tools that we have provided them okay
because we're also about future focus
you know the world is about data there's
a lot of data that obviously has an
insurer you generate is there a loan of
AI and machine learning at this point of
time for general insurance non-life
insurance oh definitely I mean as
someone's an insurance the original data
industry right it's it was the industry
which started working on data they all
actually actuarial tables and actuarial
science yeah came from insurance
industry but frankly I mean for all the
data that insurance actuaries use the
insurance industry has been a late
entrant into the AI AM L field so we
have had a few initial last say year and
a half we have been working on I am and
we have a couple of things which are on
e in production which uses the AI 2-0 to
adapt you know one is the break-in
inspection using AI so when in a
portable see your motor-pod c lapses you
have not needed in time so if you go for
issuance of policy typically someone
will tell you that we have a cup and co
vehicle so that in the three or four
days you're on and had an accident which
you want so there instead of someone
coming and visiting you which can take
up to maybe 48 to 72 hours after you
intimate the company what we have done
is given you instead in suspect tool
which is on your mobile you can have you
all you need to do is take photographs
of the vehicle there is a kind of
Skelton given which you which angles you
have to take the photograph and once you
take the photographs you upload the
photographs it takes about 10 minutes to
take the photographs from all angles
then you upload the photograph and
within about couple of minutes you get
if there is no dent on your vehicle you
will get approval saying that okay you
can pay whatever the policy amount and
your policies issued so it doesn't need
up for the inspection for
there's AI which is figuring out whether
there's any dent or there's any scratch
on your vehicle if that small scratch
it's kind of was that if the flip side
is if the resident while the AI can
reject it right now but you don't kind
of allow the AI to ejected we just send
it to a manual spoken person who can
inspect the photograph and say yes there
is a dead either you repair a tent or
you exclude it and from your policies
that we don't see again with AI you need
to realize one thing I mean right now in
in the early stages you want to use it
to benefit the customer say ok I'll
speed up the customer but if there is
some negative distance that air has to
take you'd rather let a human take it
yes but because we're still more
comfortable with human judgement it's a
blended model that you follow that have
to be rejected by a human okay
acceptance can be done by the rejection
has to be done by so even in case of
medical cashless for corporate business
for the corporate health policies fee
for the cashless claims we have a ai
looking at the when you go to the
hospital the doctor kind of fills out
your diagnosis they say you have X Y Z
this end and this is the time you need
to stay in the hospital this is a room
and you take that along with your pulse
here or at EPA desk and without your
forms and give it there typically it'll
take about 2 to 4 hours if you're lucky
and sometimes it can take quite long to
get that approval list right there again
we are using AI and here the AI is kind
of reading what a doctor has written of
course type dot is not written otherwise
I won't they have of you to figure out
what it is absolutely yeah and but it's
typed out unstructured right the doctor
is using its own their own language
abbreviations is everything which is
which a typic it's not nothing
in the US if you go there is proper
icd-10 codification for every kind of so
so when a particular code is given you
know exactly what is the treatment
process to be followed so here it's just
five or six sent in by what it is and
sense of so the AI is actually reading
that and trying to figure out whether it
fits into policy terms and conditions so
it's a gireesh is this a new normal this
is a new normal that in the Indians have
to get used to there is going to be AI
going forward and this pandemic is only
sped up our usage of these technologies
you see even your channel partners use
it and even you know the entire chain of
hospitals maybe what is your opinion
yeah I would say that this would be the
new normal there would be more and more
robotics and stuff coming in for example
I have been reading articles and how the
PPO industry is coming to terms with
having this whole work from home thrust
upon them and a lot of it has to do with
automation pots which come to their help
in trying to get doing the simple tasks
which humans can do automate them
further and lot of that because of the
improvements in natural language
processing which are there today can be
accomplished by BOTS interesting
interesting answer and but this
behavioral change in teams do you see
yourself asking them to rescale
themselves or is this but as you said
it's going to assist a chap assist in
agent right it'll be more intuitive
learning rather than risking well let me
put it this way in at least in our
business and I would say this will
largely hold true for a economy like
India as compared to say a Western
developed economy we are still growing
and I mean forget the temporary setback
the dis pandemic is in general be a crow
we are still developing and you know
when your businesses grow helps you to
do is manage for example the stuff that
I spoke of right
we actually have doctors on our rolls
who are in our claim processing center
who are actually reading that dr. agnes
is written by a doctor and then
determining whether this is so now the
AI is doing a part of the work the
doctor can do for simple cases AI just
today even today it does about 45% of
the cashless for corporate health
policies in a straight-through mode the
remaining 55% still goes to doctors but
what last year my claims would have
increased but I would not have had to
increase my workforce for handling this
thing because the doctors can now look
at the more complex claims but as the
most simple games are handled by the air
so it helps you to utilize your
workforce much better than I mean for a
doctor to read a simple maternity claim
and spend time on that no it's it's
something that it goes straight through
but if there's a comorbidity claim by
them
someone has malaria and typhoid and then
you are trying to figure out what is the
claim that is something which at least
in the current context may not be able
to do because there's not enough data on
such cases that is there for the past to
kind of print the future and you would
want to put some human intelligence into
trying to estimate what that amount is
and so here you can play segregate to
more complex tasks which human would
want to handle and let AI handle
something which is routine and
regularly okay how tough was it for you
to get this behavior change from channel
partners when you went through this
process of digital transformation was it
easy for you did you sit them down and
say okay this is our coming forward in
the future we're going to be using AI if
you're gonna be using a lot of data it
is only going to help you you want to
talk about that digital transformation
side that you enable them to be part of
so any digital any change has to be
thought through it has you have to kind
of do a lot of communication you have to
do a lot of change management because
it's just not easy throwing a digital
solution at someone and saying that okay
use it because there are going to be a
lot of issues that I mean if someone
doesn't want to use something you just
raise ten issues it doesn't work right
blame the system yes so none of that he
also comes with what are the incentives
you and incentives can be what they can
be hidden because for example something
like the email what I talked about well
I didn't really have to do it instant
because what was the alternative why did
we go for the email solution and I just
stepped back a bit to tell you how this
whole thing came about because three
four years back when we said we have to
concentrate on the SME business and we
really don't have any kind of market
share but talking about an SME business
and we need to address that one of the
first things a team on the ground came
back and said look the PS you have a
stranglehold on this business and the
reason they have stranglehold is that
this whole market is not in the big
cities it is in the Tier three and so
there there's a huge branch network that
DPS you have and there it is
and each other prophesize underwriter
them so they are kind of taking the
distance out there on the spot locally
in our case everything is centralized or
at least in hubs so for for any decision
on writing this
information to come back send to the
center some underwriter is going to put
that I mean the Gila multiple stuff out
there so it might take a day it might
take two days it might take three days
for the underwriter to revert and then
by that time the agent on the unit has
lost the case because there's always
competition out there who the if they're
able to address need fast input now what
happens when you automate it put it on
email and within five minutes the agent
is able to get done so you really don't
need to incentivize them further to get
absolutely and what about you know
there's a lot of fraud that happens in
insurance starting from the payment site
identity theft to you know to people
stealing information
can I detect fraud and insurance yeah
definitely I mean there is a lot of AI
can do it man you just had died system
and it barely starting a journey there
we've earlier for fraud detection we
used to have risk based models where
based on past claim data be used to kind
of have a model which then looked at
claims coming and it was lack of claims
based on certain triggers right say X
Hospital
whitey sees this amount of claim could
be a possible fraud police triggered an
investigation now same thing we have now
replaced with the yeah and what is the
advantage over here the model is dynamic
so it's not a static model in the
displace water typically every quarter
you take the data out kind of analyze it
then reset your triggers and that goes
here ai is more dynamic because it's
running on a constant feedback loop as
the cases come and as the cases get
triggered and you get a feedback that
disfigure is correct dai improves itself
so that we've already put that for
triggering inner health claims portfolio
we set off triggers using yeah and over
last maybe about five six months now
we've already managed to bring it to
same level of efficiency as a
current risk based model trigger model
is so so it's more prescriptive today
are predictive yeah one so it's more
predictive it's it's kind of trying to
predict that this will be a likely fraud
so we anyway have to investigate the
fraud and ETL it's just not this one
here prediction that but it is trying to
print it it's time to make our
investigation more the babies made a
success of it is that I the more
positive investigations I do okay you
know I'm gonna I want you to quickly to
talk about cyber security also the world
is moving digital digital transformation
is real everybody is now setting
objectives to digital transformation but
we need to understand risk better
there's so many security products out
there I mean thousands of tools I mean
in fact running into hundreds of
thousands for you as a know as a person
who understands tech out tough is it for
you to understand this subject and omen
on the right approach this I know
definitely I mean cybersecurity is
something that we need to pay very very
minut attention to especially when we
are now in a completely different
environment from where we see in a you
know kind of office environment it's
it's a kind of I would say sterile
environment to try and create a sterile
environment people can work from when
suddenly everyone is working from home
you're you've gone completely outside a
sterile environment you not kind of need
to manage that whole process and there
are tools out there which we are also
using to provide this cyber security but
I think while tools are required and you
need to put all that in place a key
thing in cyber security is in terms of
educating your I mean that is that is
the importance of that cannot be
understated because more breaches happen
do too
some internal employee getting fished or
some social engineering done on an
employee employee and his password
didn't compromise dan actually some
reach in the firewall of course breach
in fire was happened but it's more the
more of the attacks have been by you to
keep educating your employees you need
to keep set and especially inside we
almost send almost every day we send a
different kind of cyber cyber security
measures to employee single this is
these are the and it is true that due to
the covert related formation that is out
there a lot of people have registered
website for covert 19 and similar the
descendant they're trying to do various
kind of fishing as we need to keep
educating employees not only on this but
also so we regularly run anti-phishing
campaigns on employees so basically
anyone who gets fished by that has to go
through a learning module on how not to
get fish so those you run all these
awareness this so you hope that you are
better prepared to water because your
first line of defense is actually your
employees they have you are able to
resist attacks better okay my final two
questions here do you see a convergence
of your EIN leader science teams and
actuarial teams you know along with your
products team where you can create data
led products that are even more superior
post the overt one in a way yes I mean
because in some of the products that we
have filed in the regulatory sandbox as
well we are trying to test out these
ideas in terms of the products on
especially using telematics and motor
insurance and stuff where the data
science team works along with the
product team and actually a team to
design a product which can be giving the
customer insurance on basis of how he
drives or how much he drives so those
are products which we are testing out in
the
Arius angles nice nice oh I look forward
to more of such products my final
question is your employees you know all
of our employees look for answers you're
a leader how does a technology officer
communicate my ideas to the teams out
there and ICICI Lombard what type of
policies have you brought in during this
pandemic you know any thoughts on there
well uh one thing with first thing we
did is upload a work from home policy to
ensure that people working from home
have a good idea of what they need to do
precautions do need to take while
working from home because that was an
environment completely new for all of
them plus providing them to looks for
collaboration across because when
everyone is stuck at their homes but you
still have to collaborate on various
doing presentations together or document
together how do you use tools which are
then those toys and of course video
conferencing and stuff like that to keep
in touch so all that has been kind of
put together to enable employees to work
as seamlessly as possible without
physically interacting with each other
it has based on feedback that we get
worked out quite well so far even
employees who haven't been who in the
initial lot did not get laptops have now
been enabled to work using telephones
and their mobile phone so to that extent
we try to reach out to as many employees
as possible
and have tried to keep them engaged
through this whole
read process great answers you know you
have the toughest job possible but also
a beautiful job because the future is
about theta and using AI to predict and
prescript how humans can live better
Greece thank you very much for being on
the first episode of future focus ring
and I see you another side of the
lockdown stay safe
Thank You Stacey
[Music]